I've got some really good news on the
human brain organoids you know the
little tiny human brains we grow from
stem cells they may now be a viable
treatment for strokes this and the way
that we've been treating stem cells in
medicine may have been entirely wrong a
group of researchers induced Strokes in
experimental mice they then did two
things with the mice's brains they took
the brain organoids human in nature it's
makes more sense because it tells us
whether or not we can use them in human
studies and they implanted the brain
organoids into the region where they
induced the stroke they also took stem
cells from humans and Seed the brain
with those as well what we already know
about the brain organoids is that if you
implant them into a damaged brain early
on like a newborn they can take over and
do a very good job and make axial
projections into the whole brain and
even form hybridized neurons with the
host for the stroke experiment they did
not work with newborn mice they worked
with adult mice what they found was that
when they just seated it with stem cells
the stem cells did not survive and those
mice did not recover from a stroke but
the mice who were given a intact human
brain organoid and in their case they
put multiple brain organoids in there
they were able to heal form axial
connections and interestingly those
axial connections went all the way down
into the mice's brain stem these are by
the way fluorescent stainings of the
mice's brains it was not a perfect
recovery but the mice did recover almost
completely after around 180 days what we
don't know at this point point is if the
recovery would have been better had they
have used Mist brain organoids rather
than human but this is very very
exciting for treating Strokes in human
beings